Hello everyone and welcome back to another great lesson with EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod的另一堂精彩课程。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
Erika, today we have a great intermediate lesson.
Erika，今天我们有一堂很棒的中级课程。
That's right.
没错。
We've got a lesson about love.
我们有一堂关于爱情的课程。
About love.
关于爱情。
And about apologizing.
还有关于道歉。
Ah, okay.
啊，好吧。
Love and apologizing.
爱情和道歉。
They go together.
它们总是相伴而行。
Yes, they do.
是的，确实如此。
Especially if you have a girlfriend or boyfriend, right?
特别是如果你有男朋友或女朋友，对吧？
That's true.
没错。
Okay, so why don't we start by looking at our vocabulary preview.
好，那我们不如先来看看词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
In today's vocabulary preview, we will learn two important words from our dialogue.
在今天的词汇预览中，我们将学习对话中的两个重要单词。
What's the first word?
第一个词是什么？
Knock over.
撞倒。
So that's a really simple one.
这个词很简单。
When you knock something over, you make it fall down.
当你撞倒某物时，你让它倒下了。
Make it fall down.
让它倒下。
Yep.
是的。
So speaking of knocking things over, this morning I knocked over my coffee cup all over
说到撞倒东西，今天早上我把咖啡杯撞倒了，咖啡洒得
my desk.
满桌子都是。
Yeah, I saw that.
是啊，我看到了。
You almost ruined our lesson plan for today.
你差点毁了我们今天的课程计划。
Yes, I did.
是的，我确实差点。
It was all over the place.
到处都是。
Okay, let's look at our second word.
好，我们来看第二个词。
Explode.
爆炸。
So, when something explodes, this is what happens.
所以，当某物爆炸时，就是这种情况。
All right, that's pretty clear.
好的，这很清楚。
That's more than clear, I think.
我觉得这再清楚不过了。
So now we've looked at our two vocabulary preview words for this dialogue and we are
现在我们看完了这段对话的两个词汇预览词，我们
ready to listen to it for the first time.
准备好第一次听它了。
What's going on?
发生什么事了？
Watch out!
小心！
Hey, watch where you're going.
嘿，看着点路。
Oh no, I'm so sorry.
哦不，非常抱歉。
Are you all right?
你没事吧？
Oh, I don't know.
哦，我不知道。
I feel terrible.
我感觉糟透了。
I really didn't mean to knock you over.
我真的不是故意把你撞倒的。
My tire just exploded and I lost control of my bike.
我的轮胎刚刚爆了，我失去了对自行车的控制。
Really it was an accident.
真的，这是个意外。
Please accept my apologies.
请接受我的道歉。
Just let me try to stand up.
让我试着站起来。
Oh, wait a second, you seem really familiar.
哦，等一下，你看起来很眼熟。
I think I know you from somewhere.
我觉得我在哪儿见过你。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
I think we've met somewhere before.
我想我们以前在哪儿见过。
We met at Aaron's place last weekend.
我们上周末在亚伦家见过。
What a coincidence.
真巧。
But anyway, I'm glad to see you're not badly hurt and I should probably get going.
不过，很高兴看到你伤得不重，我可能得走了。
I've got a nine o'clock meeting.
我九点有个会。
But here's my number.
这是我的电话号码。
Call me and we'll exchange insurance information.
给我打电话，我们交换一下保险信息。
Ouch, my ankle.
哎哟，我的脚踝。
I think it's broken.
我想它断了。
You can't just leave me like this.
你不能就这样丢下我。
Are you calling an ambulance?
你在叫救护车吗？
Nope, I'm canceling my appointment so that I can stay here with you.
不，我在取消我的约会，这样我就能留下来陪你。
I love happy endings.
我喜欢大团圆结局。
Such a romantic dialogue.
多么浪漫的对话。
Yeah, this guy, oh my God, he is amazing.
是啊，这家伙，天哪，他太棒了。
I would love to meet a guy like that.
我也想遇到这样的男人。
Like that, like crashing into you?
像那样，撞到你？
Maybe not like that.
也许不是那样。
Okay, well I think it's time to look at some of the language in this dialogue.
好了，我想是时候看看这段对话中的一些语言点了。
Let's start with our language takeaway.
我们从语言要点开始。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Today we have three important words from our dialogue that we will learn for our language
今天我们从对话中学三个重要的词，作为我们的语言
takeaway.
要点。
The first word is familiar.
第一个词很熟悉。
Familiar.
熟悉。
This one, I think, is a little bit hard to explain.
这个，我觉得有点难解释。
Yeah, so let's listen to some examples on how we use familiar.
是的，我们来听一些关于如何使用“familiar”的例子。
Example one.
例子一。
Norman Clark.
诺曼·克拉克。
That name sounds familiar.
这个名字听起来很耳熟。
Where have I heard it before?
我以前在哪里听过？
Example two.
例子二。
Do you know where we are?
你知道我们在哪里吗？
I have no idea.
我不知道。
Nothing looks familiar.
没有一样东西看起来眼熟。
I think we're lost.
我想我们迷路了。
Example three.
例子三。
You look really familiar.
你看起来很面熟。
Did we go to high school together?
我们是一起上的高中吗？
So when something's familiar, you think you know it, but you're not exactly sure.
所以当某样东西很熟悉时，你觉得你认识它，但又不完全确定。
Exactly, familiar.
没错，就是熟悉。
Okay, our next word is place.
好的，我们的下一个词是“place”。
Place.
地方。
Aaron's place.
亚伦的家。
Exactly.
没错。
So when we refer to place, we refer to house.
所以当我们提到“place”时，我们指的是房子。
Right, so I can say, hey Marco, come over to my place for dinner tonight.
对，所以我可以这样说：嘿，马可，今晚来我家吃饭吧。
Exactly, or I could say, we're having a party at my place tonight at eight.
没错，或者我可以说：今晚八点在我家有个派对。
You might ask someone, how's your new place?
你可能会问别人：你的新家怎么样？
Right.
对。
How's your new apartment?
你的新公寓怎么样？
Exactly, that's a good one.
没错，这个说法很好。
So place, it's a house.
所以“place”就是房子。
Right.
对。
Our final word today is coincidence.
我们今天最后一个词是“coincidence”。
Coincidence.
巧合。
So, again, we have some great examples for you to understand how we use coincidence.
所以，我们又有一些很好的例子来帮助你理解如何使用“coincidence”。
Example one.
例子一。
I'm going to New York this weekend.
我这周末要去纽约。
What a coincidence, I am too.
真巧，我也是。
Example two.
第二个例子。
By coincidence, everyone in the room was named Alex.
巧合的是，房间里每个人都叫亚历克斯。
Example three.
第三个例子。
We met by pure coincidence.
我们完全是偶然相遇的。
One day we ran into each other on our bikes and we've been together ever since.
有一天我们骑自行车撞见了对方，从那以后就在一起了。
A coincidence is something that happens by chance, right?
巧合就是偶然发生的事情，对吧？
Right, you didn't plan it, it just happened.
对，你没有计划，它就发生了。
Yeah, these funny little things happen all the time.
是啊，这些有趣的小事经常发生。
I love it when these coincidences happen.
我喜欢这种巧合发生的时候。
Yeah, they're great.
是啊，太棒了。
So Erica, why don't you tell us about a coincidence that's happened to you?
那么埃里卡，你给我们讲讲你遇到的巧合吧？
Well, the other night I was having dinner in a restaurant and I looked up and I saw
嗯，前几天晚上我在一家餐厅吃饭，抬头一看，看到了
my old professor from university.
我大学时的老教授。
It was such a coincidence because here we are in Shanghai and I see my professor from
真是太巧了，我们在上海，而我看到了我在
Canada having dinner at the table next to me.
加拿大的教授就在我旁边的桌子吃饭。
It was such a coincidence.
真是太巧了。
That is a coincidence.
那真是个巧合。
Yeah.
是啊。
Or has it ever happened to you that you're thinking of someone and that person calls
或者你有没有过这样的经历，你正想着某人，那个人就给你打
you?
电话了？
That happens all the time.
这种事经常发生。
That's a coincidence.
那就是巧合。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
Okay, so now that we have learned these three language takeaway words, we can listen to
好了，现在我们学会了这三个语言要点，我们可以再听一遍
our dialogue a second time but this time it's going to be slower.
对话，但这次会慢一些。
Hey, watch where you're going.
嘿，看着点路。
Oh no, I'm so sorry.
哦不，非常抱歉。
Are you all right?
你没事吧？
Oh, I don't know.
哦，我不知道。
I feel terrible.
我感觉糟透了。
I didn't mean to knock you over.
我不是故意撞倒你的。
My tire just exploded and I lost control of my bike.
我的轮胎爆了，我控制不住自行车了。
Really, it was an accident.
真的，这是个意外。
Please accept my apologies.
请接受我的道歉。
Just let me try to stand up.
让我试着站起来。
Oh, wait a second.
哦，等一下。
You seem really familiar.
你看起来很眼熟。
I think I know you from somewhere.
我觉得我在哪儿见过你。
Yeah, I think we have met somewhere before.
是啊，我觉得我们以前在哪儿见过。
That's right.
没错。
We met at Aaron's place last weekend.
我们上周末在亚伦家见过。
What a coincidence.
真巧啊。
But anyway, I'm glad to see that you're not badly hurt and I should probably get going.
不过，看到你伤得不重我很高兴，我该走了。
I have a nine o'clock meeting.
我九点有个会。
But here's my number.
这是我的电话号码。
Call me and we'll exchange insurance information.
打给我，我们交换一下保险信息。
Ouch, my ankle.
哎哟，我的脚踝。
I think it's broken.
我觉得它断了。
You can't just leave me like this.
你不能就这样丢下我。
Are you calling an ambulance?
你在叫救护车吗？
No, I'm canceling my appointment so that I can stay here with you.
不，我在取消我的约会，这样我就能留下来陪你。
Well, that was much clearer, wasn't it?
嗯，这下清楚多了，对吧？
Yes, that was clear.
是的，很清楚。
And this brings us to Fluency Builder.
这就带我们进入流利度训练环节。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
In today's Fluency Builder, we're going to show you different ways of apologizing.
在今天的流利度训练中，我们将展示不同的道歉方式。
It's so important to be able to apologize well and fluently.
能够得体且流利地道歉非常重要。
Exactly.
没错。
And you also want to say something different from I'm sorry.
而且你也想说点除了“对不起”之外的话。
Right.
对。
So that's what we're going to show you today.
所以这就是我们今天要展示的内容。
We heard some great expressions for I'm sorry in the dialogue.
我们在对话中听到了一些表达“对不起”的好说法。
Let's listen now.
现在我们来听一下。
I'm so sorry.
我非常抱歉。
I feel terrible.
我感觉糟透了。
Please accept my apologies.
请接受我的道歉。
I'm so sorry.
我非常抱歉。
I feel terrible.
我感觉糟透了。
Please accept my apologies.
请接受我的道歉。
Yeah, I feel terrible.
是啊，我感觉糟透了。
I say this one all the time.
我经常说这句。
Yeah, it's a great way of saying I'm sorry.
是啊，这是表达“对不起”的好方法。
Now, also, if you want to say I'm sorry, you also want to tell the person that you made
另外，如果你想道歉，你也要告诉对方你犯了错，对吧？
a mistake, right?
没错。
That's true.
我们在对话中确实听到了一些表达“我犯错了”的好说法。
And we did hear some wonderful expressions for I made a mistake in this dialogue.
我不是故意把你撞倒的。
I didn't mean to knock you over.
这是个意外。
It was an accident.
我不是故意把你撞倒的。
I didn't mean to knock you over.
It was an accident.
这是个意外。
Well, I didn't mean to knock my coffee cup over this morning.
嗯，我今天早上也不是故意打翻咖啡杯的。
Exactly.
没错。
It was an accident.
这是个意外。
It was.
确实是。
Not on purpose, right?
不是故意的，对吧？
Or so you think.
或者你是这么想的。
Okay.
好吧。
So all of these phrases are really useful and great for apologizing and telling someone
所有这些短语都非常有用，很适合用来道歉和告诉别人
you made a mistake.
你犯了个错误。
Well, it's time for us to listen to our dialogue a third time.
好了，是时候让我们第三次听对话了。
This time it will be at its normal speed and I think you'll be able to understand a little
这次会以正常语速播放，我想你会理解得
bit better.
更好一些。
Whoa!
哇！
What's going on?
怎么了？
Watch out!
小心！
Hey, watch where you're going.
嘿，看着点路。
Oh, no.
哦，不。
I'm so sorry.
非常抱歉。
Are you alright?
你没事吧？
Oh, I'm fine.
哦，我没事。
I'm fine.
我没事。
Ugh, I don't know.
呃，我不知道。
I feel terrible.
我感觉糟透了。
I really didn't mean to knock you over.
我真的不是故意把你撞倒的。
My tire just exploded and I lost control of my bike.
我的轮胎突然爆了，我失去了对自行车的控制。
Really, it was an accident.
真的，这是个意外。
Please accept my apologies.
请接受我的道歉。
Just let me try to stand up.
让我试着站起来。
Why do birds suddenly appear?
为什么鸟儿突然出现？
Oh, wait a second.
哦，等一下。
You seem really familiar.
你看起来很眼熟。
I think I know you from somewhere.
我觉得我在哪儿见过你。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
I think we've met somewhere before.
我想我们以前见过面。
We met at Aaron's place last weekend.
我们上周末在亚伦家见过。
What a coincidence.
真巧。
But anyway, I'm glad to see you're not badly hurt, and I should probably get going.
不过，很高兴看到你伤得不重，我可能得走了。
I've got a nine o'clock meeting.
我九点有个会。
But here's my number.
这是我的电话号码。
Call me and we'll exchange insurance information.
打给我，我们交换保险信息。
Ouch!
哎哟！
My ankle!
我的脚踝！
I think it's broken.
我觉得它断了。
You can't just leave me like this!
你不能就这样丢下我！
Are you calling an ambulance?
你在叫救护车吗？
Nope.
不。
I'm canceling my appointment so that I can stay here with you.
我在取消我的约会，这样就能留下来陪你。
Great dialogue and great music, right?
很棒的对话和很棒的音乐，对吧？
Awful music.
难听的音乐。
Who picked that, Marco?
谁选的，马可？
Of course, me.
当然是我。
I'm a romantic type.
我是个浪漫的人。
I love romantic music.
我喜欢浪漫的音乐。
Really?
真的吗？
Yes.
是的。
Well, speaking of a romantic type, do you believe in love at first sight?
嗯，说到浪漫的人，你相信一见钟情吗？
I kind of do.
我有点相信。
Really?
真的吗？
I'd like to believe it.
我愿意相信。
Yeah, well...
是啊，嗯……
That surprises me.
这让我很惊讶。
Well, I think the first time that you see someone, it impresses you some way, and you
嗯，我觉得第一次见到某人时，对方会以某种方式给你留下印象，然后你
feel attracted to that person.
会被那个人吸引。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
What is the first feeling that you get that makes you want to talk to that person or get
你第一次感觉到想和那个人说话或了解
to know that person?
那个人是什么感觉？
I am the exact opposite.
我完全相反。
Really?
真的吗？
When I see somebody for the first time, my first impression is, oh, it's wrong.
当我第一次见到某人时，我的第一印象是，哦，这是错的。
So if I see someone and I like them at the beginning, in three weeks I'll hate them.
所以如果我一开始喜欢一个人，三周后我就会讨厌他。
And if I see someone and I don't like them when I first meet them, I'll be their best
如果我第一次见面时不喜欢一个人，我反而会成为他最好的
friend.
朋友。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
So love at first sight doesn't work for me.
所以一见钟情对我不起作用。
I'm sure that our listeners have some stories that love at first sight.
我相信我们的听众有一些关于一见钟情的故事。
Maybe they've met their wives or their boyfriends in this way.
也许他们就是这样遇到自己的妻子或男朋友的。
I'd like to hear about it.
我很想听听。
Me too.
我也是。
And if anybody knows the name of the songs we used, also be sure to post it on the discussion
如果有人知道我们用的歌曲的名字，也请务必在讨论
board.
板上发帖。
That's right.
没错。
Our challenge for this week.
我们这周的挑战。
Our challenge for this lesson.
我们这节课的挑战。
Yeah.
嗯。
So that's all for today, everyone, but be sure to go to our website at EnglishPod.com
今天就到这里，大家记得访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com
and as we said, leave all your comments, your stories, and see if you know the name of the
就像我们说的，留下你的评论、故事，看看你是否知道这些
songs.
歌名。
Okay, well, thanks for listening, everyone, and until next time, goodbye.
好了，感谢大家的收听，下次再见，拜拜。
Bye.
再见。